Whoever gets to the temple first, wins!
Let's get him!
Hurry up!
Hi, Nima.
Good morning, Aang.
Hey, my mirror.
Oh, hello, Aang.
Oh, perfect timing.
I don't mind giving me a lift.
Piazzo, this isn't the best time.
I'm getting old, you know.
My body doesn't move like it used to.
I'm kind of in the middle of something.
You are so heavy.
Heavy?
Me?
I eat nothing but vegetables.
Pie is not a vegetable.
I'm gonna lose the race.
Race?
What race?
We finally are!
We won!
Aang, as an airbender, it's important
that you know when to show restraint.
Even if you have the power
to win, you are the Avatar.
A lot of people are
going to rely on the Isle.
He's gone!
He ran away!
What?
I'm here!
Where's the Avatar?
Aang, where are you?
Piazzo, I'm here!
I'm here!
Hey, Momo.
Hi, Appa.
Was I asleep for long?
Okay, okay.
I'm awake already.
I know, I know.
We've got a job to finish.
Let's continue our journey.
Back to our old home.
This may not have been
our best trip, but any
airbender relic we find
makes it all worthwhile.
This could be the oldest
piece in our collection.
So numb.
I miss you.
Momo, go outside with Appa.
Now!
Who are you?
Why are you doing this?
Please, stop!
I don't want to hurt you.
Where is it?
Nope, that's not it.
Hey!
Those are antiques!
Enough!
Wait!
I found it!
Zonam, why ain't after you?
Wait!
No, that's a thousand years old!
Give it to me!
Why don't we just talk?
Maybe I can help.
We don't need your help, Avatar.
We're done living in a world where Vendors
have all the power and we have none!
Who are you?
We're the Denied!
The Denied?
Just kill him already!
No!
He'll bring the whole place down!
have all the power and we have none.
Who are you?
We're the Denied!
The Denied?
Just kill him already!
No! He'll bring the whole place down!
You... saved me.
Kaliq! Grab the map! Let's go!
Oh no!
I'm fine. Momo, I'm fine.
We've got to get to Republic City.
Appa, yip yip!
I'm fine. Momo, I'm fine.
We've got to get to Republic City.
Appa, yip yip!
I'm fine. Momo, I'm fine.
We've got to get to Republic City.
Appa, yip yip!
I'm fine. Momo, I'm fine.
We've got to get to Republic City.
Appa, yip yip!
Yip yip!
Water.
Her tribes gather strength from the moon.
And flow with the tides.
Earth.
A kingdom of unshakable will.
Reliable and strong.
Fire.
A nation capable of great destruction.
But also... of great warmth.
Air.
Peaceful nomads with
the power of a hurricane.
But the spirit of a gentle breeze.
For generations, the
Avatar, the one master of
all four elements, kept
the nations in balance.
But when that responsibility
fell to me as a child, I ran away.
I was caught in a deadly storm.
But my Avatar spirit
preserved me in a sphere
of energy where I stayed
for a hundred years.
I woke to discover that
the balance preserved
by the Avatar had
been destroyed by war.
The air nomads were gone.
All but one.
me.
I could no longer run from
my responsibility as the Avatar.
I found allies from every nation.
Benders.
And non-benders.
Katara taught me how to water bend.
Toph trained me in the
ways of the Earthbenders.
Zuko, once my worst enemy,
became my firebending teacher.
Sokka showed me that bravery is the
most important part of being a leader.
We became a family.
And together, we ended
the Hundred Year War.
Then, we began the hard
work of rebuilding the world.
For so long, the nation stood apart, alone.
And we all suffered as a result.
But here, on this ancient site, we created
a place where all people are welcome.
Bender and non-bender alike.
Working together in
peace to build the future.
Though there are still those who
would seek to divide us, we remain united.
As a council representative, I am
honored to be here today, celebrating
the anniversary of Republic City
and the opening of Unity Tower.
A symbol for all people.
Look!
It's the Avatar!
Let's hurry!
Oh.
Momo!
Appa!
I missed you too, old friend.
Aang!
Katara!
You're hurt.
Take a deep breath.
And... Exhale.
I've heard the Deneid
are growing in numbers,
but they've never done anything like this.
Attacking the Avatar?
Yeah.
They were incredible fighters.
Even without bending.
Oops!
Ow!
Breathe through it.
Be honest.
You're enjoying this.
Aang, this is serious.
Whatever this map they took was, if they
were willing to kill the Avatar to get it,
what else are they willing to do?
I don't know.
I'm worried about you.
You're spending more and
more time at the Air Temple.
Alone.
It's... how I hold
on to my past.
I know how hard this is for you.
When I was attacked,
all I could think about
was that... this could be it.
I'm the last Airbender.
If I die,
my culture dies with me.
You may be the last Airbender.
But you're not alone.
You're not alone.
Aang,
none of this would exist without you.
You made the city possible
with your heart and your mind.
Because of you,
all of the nations live here.
Together.
All except mine.
I know.
But the people here
still need your protection.
You're an Airbender.
But you're also the Avatar.
You're right.
Whoever this Sonam person
is, I need to find out more.
Aang.
Avatar Roku.
It is good to see you again.
How can I help you?
In your lifetime, did you ever hear of
an ancient Airbender named Sonam?
I have not.
But you have many past lives to call upon.
Perhaps one further back in
the Avatar Cycle can help you.
Thank you, Avatar.
Roku.
I'm sorry.
I've never heard her say.
Perhaps earlier.
Not here.
We're back in the Avatar Cycle.
We're back in the back of the Cycle.
Um, hello?
Is there anyone here?
Hello?
Who calls upon Avatar Sion's
vast wealth of knowledge?
Oh, hello.
You look like an Avatar from
a time quite distant from mine.
Please, please, tell me about your era.
What are people wearing?
Are sandals still a thing?
Uh, yes.
Oh, why?
Why, after so many years, open toes,
seeing someone else's crusty cuticles?
Disgusting!
Right.
Anyway, I have come through your guidance.
You see, I was attacked.
It was not me, okay?
It wasn't me.
I know that.
I think it might have something to
do with an airbender named Sonam.
Hmm.
Sonam.
It sounds familiar.
Where have I heard that name before?
Aha!
Sonam was the youngest
daughter of the owner of
the possum chicken shop
at the corner marketplace.
Wait.
That was my ex, Soniam.
If only she didn't have
those humongous toenails.
Ugh, disgusting.
This is going nowhere.
Sonam?
Well, thank you for your time.
I must continue my search.
Oh!
Sonam!
You're asking about the
legend of the lost Avatar.
Sonam was an Avatar?
Indeed she was!
She was the Avatar in the
golden age of airbenders.
Legend said she had a staff
that could channel the vast energy
of the spirit world, granting
its keeper unlimited power.
Is-is that even possible?
Eh, we'll never know for sure.
Many Avatars have tried to
communicate with her, but they couldn't.
She disappeared so completely
that it was as if she never existed.
And perhaps it's better that way.
Maybe such a staff was too
dangerous for anyone to possess.
Even the Avatar.
But-but that's exactly
why I need to find it.
The people who attacked
me discovered a map.
It must lead to the staff.
Avatar Shion.
Please.
You have to tell me where it is.
The legend says that Sonam disappeared
with her staff on the peak of Mount Baihu.
Katara.
I'm sorry to leave so suddenly.
But I found out what the denier after.
Sonam had a staff of immense power.
And in their hands, it could
be a devastating weapon.
They have a head start.
There's no time to waste.
You take Appa and Momo and
gather up the rest of the team.
We're gonna need some help.
Next on the agenda, a Fire Nation
naval vessel came into conflict
with an extremist group of
non-benders called the Denied.
They've been robbing
ancient sites- Your Majesty!
Your Majesty!
An urgent message has
arrived from Republic City!
How impudent!
Can't you see Fire Lord
Zuko's- Chamberlain.
There's only one person
who can send a message
urgent enough to interrupt
the Fire Lord's council.
Is it from the Avatar?
Yes, my lord.
Read it to me.
What are you doing?
Read it quickly.
Yes, Gwen Chamberlain.
Flame Hill Hartman, how's
ruling the Fire Nation?
I hope the boring Chamberlain you mentioned
in your letters isn't still annoying you.
Anywho, to cut to the
chase, I need your help.
Can you please come immediately?
Oh, and don't forget to
bring some firecracker buns.
Allow me to present Sokka Cycle.
Flames launch you into the sky where
you can drop water bombs on your enemies.
Then skis pop out to
help you stick the landing.
Pretty great, right?
Eh, boring.
Why would you need a sled
when you can just waterbend?
Oh, oh, oh!
Like me, like me!
Keep in mind, there are still plenty
of folks like me who can't bend.
Why would Avatar Aang
partner with a non-bender?
Why? I'll tell you why.
I saved him from the iceberg.
My boomerang flew by his side while I
carried away enemies with my trusty blade.
I even took down the whole
Fire Nation airship armada.
And on top of all that, I
was more popular than him.
You're such a liar, Sokka.
It's from the Avatar.
Wow!
Really?
Oh, so now you think I'm cool?
All right, metalbenders.
Let's see if any of you tenderfoots
can at least make me use my hands.
my hands.
I'm still the greatest
Earthbender in the world!
And I'm bored.
Master Toph, there's a bird on your head.
And?
It looks like it has a message.
Reed.
Uh, it's from Avatar Aang.
He needs your help.
It's the deni-- The
deni-- Where is he?
Mount Bayou.
Oh, my God.
No.
I love that hat.
Oh, my God.
Sonam?
Could that be you?
I'm not going to die.
Who are you?
Huh?
I don't know.
Did you come off to get yourself killed?
I thought you were
here looking for a staff.
Who's this guy?
An airbender.
How did he hold up an entire mountain?
His chi is strong, like
nothing I've ever felt.
Hey, Avatar, you think this guy beat
your record for longest frozen airbender?
Yeah, how long do you
think he was in that ice?
I don't know.
His tattoos look ancient.
He's been in there a long time.
He smells good for an old guy.
Ew.
What?
My senses tell me this
guy is pretty attractive.
Tom!
Someone else confirm.
This is serious.
What does attractive even mean?
Just give me a straight confirmation.
Is he attractive?
He's very attractive.
Huh?
What?
He is.
It's all in the bone structure.
No.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey.
Easy.
You're safe.
Earthbender!
No, no, no, we're all friends here.
It's okay.
Someone woke up on the
wrong side of the mountain.
Where is she?
Where is Avatar Sonam?
You knew Sonam?
Who are you?
I don't know how to explain it, but
you've been asleep for a long time.
I'm the Avatar now.
I'm Aang.
If you're the Avatar,
then... Sonam.
Well, Sonam might be
long gone, but on the
bright side, you woke
up at the perfect time.
Everyone will be amazed
to see another airbender.
Aang's not the last one anymore.
What do you mean, last?
The air nomads.
They've been wiped out.
There's only me.
No.
Sonam's staff.
Do you have it?
It's our only hope now.
What do you mean?
I thought it was a weapon.
The staff is no weapon.
It is a gift.
With it, Sonam was able to channel
the vast power of the spirit world.
It was this power that
allowed Jurana to flourish.
The greatest city in the world.
An air nomad utopia where
Sonam presided over a golden
age of balance and where I
devoted my life to serving her.
In return, she raised me
up and used her staff to give
me, a lowly non-bender,
the power to bend the air.
I was the first, but I
would not be the last.
She filled the skies with
airbenders, and we flew
by her side, spreading
peace across the world.
Aang, are you okay?
Sonam used the staff to
give people airbending.
If we found it, I could bring
airbending back to the world.
This is incredible!
There haven't been airbenders
for over a hundred years!
This is everything you ever wanted, Aang.
We could heal the greatest atrocity
my nation committed in the war.
This could be the final
step to rebuilding the world.
Not if the Denied get there first.
They have the map.
Who are the Denied?
A group of violent non-benders.
They... They must be after the
staff to give themselves airbending.
Then there's no time to waste.
There's only one place it could be.
Ready your bison.
We'll need to travel
across the endless ocean.
On the other side of the world?
But there's nothing out there.
There's an island.
The journey will not be easy.
But we can make it.
Then let's get going.
The skies are no place for a water child.
I know you just woke up after thousands
of years, but we do these things together.
Trust me.
We're stronger this way.
Welcome to Team Avatar.
What's your name?
Taga.
My name is Taga.
Just think of it as a big metal airbison.
We will travel ancient
paths through the sky.
Ones that our people
learned by following the great
airbison herds that long
ago taught us airbending.
Air currents known only to us.
Encircling the great sphere of existence.
Allowing us to travel where we wish.
Giving us our name.
The Air Nomads.
Allowing us to travel where we wish.
Allowing us to travel.
We wish.
Uh, no!
No!
He was frozen for 5,000 years.
Okay?
You were frozen for what?
A hundred?
Okay?
That's nothing.
Your brain is... fresh.
Maybe he is a little old-fashioned.
But look at him.
He's so in tune with his element.
He can travel across the entire ocean.
With no map.
No instruments.
There's so much I can learn from him.
I'd give anything to be able
to see my air bison again.
And now... To see
only one remains.
You said our people were wiped out.
Yet you survived.
How?
I had just found out I was the Avatar.
But... The responsibility...
It was too much.
So I ran away.
While I was gone... The
Fire Nation attacked.
They were looking for me.
If... If I'd just been
there... Sonam would say...
Air Nomads are formed from the mist.
We walk the world for a moment in time.
Then we return to the eternal wind.
Monkiazzo taught me that.
We carry the same weight.
A grief no one else could
possibly comprehend.
But you and I can heal the past.
Let me show you how
powerful our element can be.
When airbenders work together.
What are you doing?
This is how Sonam taught me.
Feel the energy that tethers us.
The bond between us.
Can you feel it?
Use it!
This is amazing!
Yes!
Woohoo!
Oh yeah!
Human boomerang!
He's actually flying.
So are we.
Whoa!
That's my best friend!
Now you throw me!
I had no idea that you were going to die.
This is only the beginning.
I can't believe it.
Airbenders will fill the sky again.
We have been given a great gift.
The chance to redeem ourselves.
You were destined to find
me on that mountain, Aang.
How did you end up there?
The Earthbenders had attacked Tirana.
Sonim and I fought
fearlessly, side by side.
We drove them back to Mount Baihu.
And that's the last I remember.
She must have saved your life.
Only an Avatar could
have put you in that sphere.
Aang, can I ask you something?
Of course.
If the Fire Nation destroyed
the Air Nomads, how
can you suffer the
presence of the Fire Lord?
Zuko is a friend and an ally.
He turned against his own
father to help me end the war.
Yet he wears the crown himself now.
Fire by its nature burns, Aang.
Our kind have always suffered at
the hands of the other elements.
That's why we built Republic City.
To show the world that if we listen
to each other, we can all live together.
In peace.
And once we bring back
Airbenders, it'll be complete.
When everyone stuck to their own,
the whole world was nearly torn apart.
And besides, Katara, Sokka,
Zuko, Toph, they're my family now.
I want to live in a world
where we can all be together.
You remind me so much of Sonom.
It's the Avatar.
And this time he's got
his friends with him.
That's the Fire Lord's airship.
How'd they get ahead of us?
They don't even have the map.
We can't risk him
getting to the staff first.
Kill him.
But he spared our lives.
And how many Countless were killed in
the hundred years waiting for his return?
Where was he when
your family was wiped out?
If we want anything to change,
we need what the Benders have.
Power.
Fire!
It's the Denied!
Oh, we are definitely under attack!
Turn them up to his friends!
Is he crushing the ship?
Targa?
Targa, stop!
We're here.
The Immortal Storm.
Oh, no.
There has to be another way around.
No.
Together, you and I can
clear a path for the ship.
But we have to go now.
Aang, trust me.
Maybe now is a good time to turn back.
I don't think that's an option anymore.
Where are they going?
The engine's out.
We're losing air pressure.
Targa, come with me.
What about me?
Take the wheel.
What?
I've only ever crashed
Fire Nation airships.
Okay, let's see.
Here's our rudder.
This is the elevator.
There's our ballast.
And there's the giant tornado
that's going to kill us all.
Follow my lead.
Work with me.
Just like I showed you.
We can heart it.
Yes, that's it, Aang.
Keep going.
Got it.
Zuko!
Aang and Targa are destroying tornadoes.
But there's too many!
But they're everywhere!
Just steer the ship.
Don't lose Aang.
It's not that easy.
Especially when everything is sideways.
Okay, left!
I did it!
Right!
Oh no!
We're falling behind!
I'm losing sight of them!
We have to go back!
Trust in your friends.
They won't make it if
we don't clear a path.
Zuko!
We're going to crash into the sea!
When I give you the signal,
pull the lever next to the wheel.
We're going to crash!
Katara?
We're going to crash into the sea!
We made it through!
Thank you, Taga!
It was you, Aang!
We're here because of you!
Yeah, we're having a good time, too!
You could have told us we were
flying into the Immortal Storm!
I know it was dangerous,
but we had to risk it!
We?
I don't remember when
we took a vote on that!
There wasn't time!
I had to make a call!
Friends, please, don't blame Aang!
This is all my fault!
I knew this would be difficult!
But Aang believed in
your strength as a team!
And I'm honored to be a part of it!
I forgive you, Taga!
Everyone!
Look!
These islands!
They were...
Lion Turtles!
Whoa!
It's beautiful!
Long before my time,
the Lion Turtles granted the
gift of bending to humans.
These are their final resting grounds.
This is where Sonam
came to learn their ways.
I am certain that she left her staff here.
Where should we start looking?
Aang, you must connect with her.
But... No one can
connect with Sona.
The spiritual power of the Lion
Turtles is still concentrated here.
Let it guide you.
We'll set out immediately.
Actually, Taga, we could
really use your help here.
If the Denied are close
behind, we need to be ready.
Yeah, and we're gonna need more
than Toph's metal bending to fix the...
My bending got us through that, Storm.
What did you do?
Steered with his feet.
Repairs can wait.
Aang needs me.
Taga, please.
Stay and help my friends.
I'll be okay on my own.
As you wish.
We will begin repairs for our voyage home.
Everyone?
I know I've asked a lot
of you on this journey.
But we're about to accomplish
something that will change the world.
Let it guide you.
Sona?
No.
Ah, this is turning out
to be a nice little vacation.
Aside from all the people trying
to kill us, and the tornadoes...
Um, we're supposed to be fixing the ship?
You're doing great, buddy.
Has anyone seen Taga?
Yes, we've all seen Taga. He's so gorgeous.
Jeez, I get it.
Oh, I see what you mean.
He wandered off that way.
No, maybe that way?
Taga! Taga! Where are you going?
Aang needs to be protected.
I agree.
I know my ways may
seem unusual to you, but
I assure you, everything
I do, I do for Aang.
For Aang? Or for the staff?
You have no idea all that we've lost.
You've never known a world with airbenders.
I know Aang. He may
be the last of his kind,
but he's the reason
this world knows peace.
His values as an air nomad
have brought balance to chaos.
It's because of Aang that the water
tribes, Earth Kingdom and Fire Nation now
work together, striving for harmony,
a peace we once thought unattainable.
You speak of peace. There will never be
peace among the elements. There never was.
Your precious Republic
City is built on lies.
It's built on hope. Do you have hope, Taga?
Saving my people requires more
than just hope. It requires sacrifice.
I saw you try to crush the Danides
airships. You were ready to kill them.
I know what kind of airbender Aang
is, but what kind of airbender are you?
Aang did well getting us here.
There is great strength in
him, but weakness as well.
Weakness?
Yes. You.
What the hog monkey?
No!
Tata!
Brother...
Taga, it's real.
We can finally bring back airbending.
Let's go tell the others.
We can do this. Me and you.
I can't do this without my friends.
Earth killed my people. Fire killed yours.
The staff is the only way we
can create a new air empire.
One capable of defending itself.
No.
We can build a new future, Taka.
But it has to be for everyone.
The staff doesn't belong to everyone.
It belongs to us.
What... what have you done?
As long as they were around, you'd
always put them ahead of our people.
Don't you see?
This is how we redeem ourselves.
It doesn't matter that you ran them.
As long as you stand with me now.
Now.
Aang!
Listen to me!
Katara!
This is the only way!
You're a traitor to your own.
Just like Sona!
No!
I wanted to do this with you by my side.
But if I must build a new
air empire alone... So be it.
So be it.
There's no way in!
We have to turn back!
No!
We keep trying to push through!
So new staff!
Denied!
The Avatar is dead!
If you wish to build a new world where
you have the power... I can give it to you!
Appa!
Katara!
They're gone!
It's all my fault!
It's always been my fault!
Ever since I ran away!
No Avatar has ever fallen into such
shame as to join me here in my sorrow.
Why do you grieve so, friend?
Avatar Sonum?
Taga murdered my friends.
And now he has a staff.
Taga!
No!
I... I stopped him!
I hit the staff!
What have you done?
You're the one who gave him airbending!
How could you give power to a monster?!
The Taga I gave bending
to was a different man.
It was a different time.
The airbenders were the
peacekeepers of the Four Elements.
We used our power to mediate
all conflict with non-violence.
But we were the fewest in numbers.
We were the fewest in numbers.
For many years, we existed in a
beautiful balance of great power.
We used our power to mediate
all conflict with non-violence.
But we were the fewest in numbers.
For many years, we existed in a
beautiful balance of great prosperity.
But the world began to shift.
The earthbenders from the ground.
Why did you give power to a monster?!
The Taga I gave bending
to was a different man.
Why did you give power to a monster?!
What did you give power to a monster?!
Did you just come from
that temple in the sky?!
I certainly did!
It was my favorite hidey hole!
Until that dark yucky energy
started corrupting this whole face!
Please!
We need your help getting up there!
It's my duty to stop this!
I'm the Avatar!
Oooh!
The Avatar!
Let me have a squeeze at you!
Okay!
Now with this eye!
And this eye!
Oh, don't forget this eye!
Can we hurry enough?!
Let me squeeze!
Sniff check!
Oh, that's Avatar material right there!
Yes, it is!
Oooh!
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
It appears the universe has brought us
together for a very important mission!
Huh?
To flee!
To be alive!
Wait!
Come back!
We're going to go away!
Stop!
Please!
Great Spirit!
Both of our worlds are in danger!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
I am not going back up there!
Hmm, well when you put it like
that, it does make more sense!
Upon reflection, I've decided I shall
help you and your humany friends!
What did he say?
Nice work, Momo!
Alright!
In you go!
By the way, no eating anything you find
in my teeth, as I'm saving that for later!
Ready!
Set!
Get steady and rent!
The one and the two and
the you know what to do!
Bluff!
I know we haven't known each
other very long, but... I love you!
You don't have to say it back!
Hey!
You got your hair back!
Why are my eyes teary?
Was I crying?
No way!
Look!
What?
What is it?
It's Republic City!
We can't let him destroy
everything we built!
We won't!
We can't let him destroy
everything we built!
We won't!
We can't let him destroy
everything we built!
We won't!
We can't let him destroy
everything we built!
Boomerang!
Give me the staff, Targa!
I see I underestimated you, Avatar.
Your friends are stronger than I thought.
But you're too late.
They're denied.
You see, I did what you wanted, Aang.
I returned airbending to the world.
What's the plan?
We'll deal with the denied.
You have to get the staff.
I will rebuild Jurana on
the ruins of our enemies.
Just as they did on ours.
A new air empire will rise.
Kill them all.
We have to get these people out of here.
Get out of here!
Help me!
Oh, yeah!
Targa!
Give it to me!
This isn't the way!
We can use the staff to bring back balance!
Peace!
You care so much about your
ideals that you'd let your people die!
I will do anything to
make sure they survive!
I will do anything to kill you!
I will kill you!
Don't do this!
You have the power now!
You can decide how to use it!
I'm not like you!
The world hasn't been good to me!
The world is what we make it!
Get away from her!
Run!
Taga!
Stop!
You betrayed me!
You betrayed our culture!
I gave you every chance to see the truth!
Shouldn't you be in the Fire Nation?!
I'm fighting for the peace of all nations!
Big talk from someone who sits at
a throne built on a century of war!
Oh!
Shouldn't you be in the Fire Nation?
I'm fighting for the peace of all nations.
Big talk from someone who sits at
a throne built on a century of war!
I'm still the greatest
Earthbender in the world!
Oh no.
I'm out of water!
We gotcha!
And there's no Avatar here to save you.
Suck a cycle!
Let's see if your fancy new bending can
beat some good old non-bending know-how.
Oh no!
Bombs away!
You just got denied!
Let's go!
Good luck saving your city!
We have to save as many people as we can!
Oh no!
I know your pain!
I know what you've been through!
You don't know!
I watched as all of my brothers
and sisters were slaughtered!
And the Fire Nation burned
the Air Nomads to ash!
Where were you?
You ran!
Ah!
Chaga!
No!
The full power of the spirit
world flows through me!
This is what strength looks like!
No!
Oh, my God.
We could have been brothers.
We could have done this together.
It didn't have to end like this.
It's Aang.
He's got the staff.
Yeah.
Kick his butt, Mega Aang.
No, something's wrong.
The power is corrupting him.
I dreamt of bringing the Air Nomads
back to the world as peacekeepers.
They could have been a beacon of light
for the world to follow, but you ruined it.
You twisted my dream into a nightmare.
Finally, you have the
power the Air Nomads need.
Maybe there is hope for you after all.
Do it.
Use the staff.
Show me you have the
strength to bring our people back.
Do it.
No! No! No! No! No! No! No! No!
Aang. You will do so many great things
as the avatar. But you must be prepared to
do what frightens you the most. Your
people, your home, we are always with you.
Aang. No!
No!
Aang!
No! My power!
Aang. No! No! No! No! No! No!
You fool! Why? Why did you break it?
We could have fixed everything!
We can't erase the pain of the past.
We couldn't save them.
But it's our duty to protect our people!
Not at the cost of betraying
everything they stood for.
No!
It's time to let go.
You have to forgive yourself.
I have to forgive myself too.
Air nomads are formed from the mist.
We walk the world for a moment in time.
Then we return to the eternal wind.
Aang!
Hey, Katara.
Hey, Aang.
Seriously?
You do realize you're falling, right?
Hey, if you ever get
tired of relying on alcohol,
I could hook you up
with one of these babies.
I'll give you the best friend discount!
I don't know if
airbending will ever return.
But I know now that the true power of
the air nomads was never their bending.
It was their values.
And that's a power I can pass on to others.
Avatar Aang, you are the true
embodiment of the air nomads.
Thank you for giving up
the power that I could not.
You give me hope for
the future of our culture.
And that's all right.
It's amazing, isn't it?
The first new air temple in centuries.
Republic City is finally complete.
A city for all nations.
Just like you promised.
I never could have done
this without you, Katara.
Hey everybody!
Sorry I kept you all waiting.
Are you ready for our big trip?
As my new acolytes,
you will be helping me
preserve our culture
for future generations.
So, who wants to search for artifacts
at an ancient abandoned temple?
Yay.
I'm only going to make sure you don't
try to release another beefy old airbender.
Yeah, I'm done with bad boys.
Mr. Sodom told me about this place.
So, it's very possible that no one's
been here in hundreds of years.
Oh!
Is this an Arbender relic?
I think that's just a rock.
But I love the enthusiasm.
Aww!
Ah!
Keep your eyes open.
They never know what
we might discover here.
Oh.
I thought they were extinct.
I can't believe it.
The original airbenders.
Oh, can I have one?
Ha, ha, ha, ha!
Apo!
Yip, yip!
Oh, can I have one?
Oh, my God.
Thank you.